I am Death,  Denny Colt.
我是死神 Denny Colt
You are the only man who has ever escaped my cold embrace.
你是唯一一个从我手掌逃脱的人
But I am never far away.
但我不会远离你的
Yes.
是的
I'm always with you.
我会一直在你身旁
- Yeah. - Something big is breaking down...
- 说 - 泥滩这里...
...by the mudflats,  Spirit.
出大事了 魂
By the wreck of an old cargo ship.
就在艘旧货船的残骸附近
Word on the street is The Octopus might be in on it.
传言章鱼先生也在虎视眈眈
I'd call it in...
我正在现场盯着...
...but who knows how far his tentacles spread?
...但谁知道他的触手能伸到哪呢?
Who we can trust?
我们还能信任谁?
l'm on my way.
我这就来
My city. She's always there for me.
我的城市 她永远都等着我
Every lonely night,  she's there for me.
在每个孤独的夜晚
She's not some tarted- up fraud all dressed up like a piece of jailbait.
她不是那种抹着香水装嫩的小妞
No. She's an old city...
她很老了...
...old and proud of her every pock and crack and wrinkle.
...老得连每一道斑痕和皱纹 都引以为傲
She's my sweetheart,  my plaything.
她就是我的情人 我的伴侣
She doesn't hide what she is, what she's made of:
她从不隐藏自己
Sweat,  muscle and blood of generations.
汗水 暴力 几代人的鲜血 都展露无遗
She sleeps.
她在沉睡
After midnight and until dawn, only shadows move in the silence.
午夜过后 拂晓之前 只有影子在寂静中飘荡
There she is!
她在那儿!
- Get her. - Damn,  I've got no time for this.
- 抓住她 - 该死 没时间了
My city screams. She needs me.
城市在尖叫 她需要我
She is my love. She is my life.
她就是我的挚爱 我的生命
And I am her Spirit.
我就是她的魂
Don't worry,  you're safe now. Try to catch your breath.
别担心 你安全了 放松些
- Here,  let's get you to your feet. - Police!
- 来 我扶你 - 警察!
Over here,  MacReady.
在这呢 MacReady
This is a good man,  you can trust him. Tell him everything.
这是个好人 你可以信任他 告诉他所发生的事吧
- l will. - Call your shrink if you got one.
- 我会的 - 可能的话 去看下心理医生
What are you?
你是什么?
That's The Spirit.
他就是魂
God bless him.
上帝保佑他
She provides for me,  my city does.
这座城市 生我养我
She gives me everything I need.
给了我所需的一切
Move it over,  Liebowitz. l'm driving.
坐过去 Liebowitz 我来开车
Sussman called.
Sussman求援
Something's going down here. Could be big.
刚才这里出大麻烦了
- How big? - Octopus big.
- 有多大? - 章鱼都来了
- Jesus! We better call for backup. - Not just yet.
- 天啊! 我们最好请求支援 - 但不是现在
Sussman wants this one kept under the radar for now.
Sussman不想打草惊蛇
Yes. Come closer. Come home to me.
再靠近点 跟我回家吧
You hear that,  boss?
头儿 听到了么?
Every goddamn night.
这鬼声音每晚都有
Lorelei. The angel of death. She's never far away. Not from me.
是Lorelei 死亡天使 她一直在我身旁
They say only sailors and cops can hear her.
据说只有水手和警察才能听到
Well,  l'm not a sailor.
我不是水手
And l'm not a cop.
也不是警察
- Officer down. - Roger that,  I copy.
- 有警员受伤 - 收到 明白
Get an ambulance. Call Dolan.
派救护车来 叫上Dolan
- Commissioner- - - Not Commissioner Dolan.
- Dolan长官? - 不是
- Dr. Dolan. - Still breathing.
- 是Dolan医生 - 他还有气
- Spirit says he's still breathing. - Keep me advised.
- 魂说他还没死 - 保持联络
Hurts like a son of a bitch.
太他妈疼了
Take it easy. We'll get you home.
放松些 我们会送你回家的
That broad.
那个女人
- You should have seen her. - Broad?
- 你应该见过她 - 女人?
A beautiful broad.
一个美丽的女人
She was beautiful.
很美
Keep him talking. Keep him awake.
跟他说话 让他保持清醒
You look for more footprints, Liebowitz.
去看看有没有其他脚印 Liebowitz
Yeah. She was beautiful.
她真的很美
lf this is the wrong box, l'll kill you myself.
如果拿错了箱子 我一定会亲手杀了你
Just get us out of here. lt's The Octopus.
快离开这儿吧 那可是章鱼先生
You know what he can do.
你知道他有多厉害
Shut up and bleed.
给我闭嘴
You look for more footprints, Liebowitz.
去看看有没有其他脚印 Liebowitz
She was beautiful.
她真的很美
And she wasn't looking for a fight,  either.
她也没想找我麻烦
Easy,  now.
放松
Just breathe through your nose if you can.
尽量呼吸
Getting dizzy.
我觉得晕
Steady. Steady.
保持呼吸
Heads up!
小心!
Take it home,  boys.
把它搬回去 伙计们
When me and The Spirit get together, we like to party all night.
每当我和魂见面时 总是要彻夜狂欢的
There is nothing l like better than kicking your ass all night long.
再没有比整晚都狂扁你更开心的事了
Except maybe eggs.
或者让你出糗哦
Where's the truck?
卡车哪去了?
Silken Floss is the most beautiful woman.
Silken Floss是最美的女人
How do we find our way home without her?
没有她 我们怎么回去啊?
She was supposed to be here.
她应该在这的啊
Where's the truck?
卡车哪去了?
l found the truck!
我找到卡车了!
Silken Floss is the most beautiful woman ever.
Silken Floss是最美的女人
Load up the box and pile in, specimens.
把箱子装上车 怪胎们
You've done your petri dishes proud.
不枉培育出你们一回
No need to wait for the boss if that's The Spirit back there.
如果魂在附近的话 就不用等老大了
The Octopus always finds his nemesis so distracting.
章鱼一见仇人就分外眼红
lt is The Spirit. He had his hat on. We was watching.
确实是魂 他还戴着那顶帽子 我们看到了
Well,  then,  they'll be at it all night.
他们会干上一整晚呢
- Yeah,  boss said so. - Boss said so. We was watching.
- 对 老大说过了 - 老大说过了 我们看着呢
Oh,  God. Yeah. l heard.
额滴神啊 我听到啦
Silken Floss is the most beautiful- -
Silken Floss是最美的--
You're giving me a headache, Octopus.
你砸得我头很痛 章鱼
lt's gonna get worse before it gets better,  pretty boy.
还有更爽的呢 帅哥
You're right about that.
说得对
Come on!
来啊!
Toilets are always funny.
厕所总是很有趣的
l was watching.
我一直在看着呢
That's enough. Let's get out of here.
够了 该走了
Pretty boy.
娘娘腔
Tough boy.
很顽强嘛
l'll be seeing you again...
我会再见到你的...
...real soon.
...很快
l'm gonna be the death of you, Octopus.
到时就是你的死期 章鱼
Death?
死期?
Not for me,  brother. Death,  he says.
你灭不了我 伙计 还我的死期
l'm gonna kill you all kinds of dead.
我要让你死无全尸
l had you beat like eggs.
我今天把你打惨了
Heck you did.
扯淡
Anybody watching could've seen l had you right where l wanted you.
是我把你逮了个正着
ln your dreams.
做梦吧
You're an accident.
你就是个意外
You never should've happened.
一个不该发生的意外
Your mind ain't right,  Octopus.
你脑子有病吧 章鱼
You're talking crazy. You're talking crazy talk.
你语无伦次 疯话连篇
We're the only two like us,  pretty boy.
其实我们有相同之处 帅哥
- l'm nothing like you. - Nothing like me?
- 一点都不像 - 不像?
Well,  you sure can take a lot of punishment,  sweetheart.
你这么耐打 是吧
Just like me.
和我一样
You ever wonder why?
想过为啥么?
Never even crossed my mind.
想都没想过
Well,  l'll be learning you!
好 我会学你的!
l'll be learning you real soon.
我很快就会学你
l'll be learning you.
我学你
Oh,  well,  look who's here.
哈 看看谁来了
Boss,  we better get out of here.
老大 我们快跑路吧
Such pain.
如此伤痛
Such suffering.
如此折磨
Sleep.
睡吧
Come on,  come on,  come on.
来吧 来吧
Wake up.
快醒来
Hey,  baby.
嘿 宝贝
- Ellen. - You're a mess.
- Ellen - 你真是一团糟
Three bullets across the deltoid.
有三颗子弹射穿了你的肌肉
They went straight through me. Hardly took any meat.
直接穿过去的 伤不了多少啦
Major contusions on any visible skin.
让我看看有什么严重的外伤
Oh,  come on,  Ellen. They never last long.
不用了 Ellen 没啥大碍
Evidence of a profusely bleeding cranial wound.
你头上的伤口还在不停流血
No,  that's nothing. That's just a bump.
没啥啦 只是撞了下而已
Yeah,  you're a mess,  all right.
你真是伤得不轻
- Really,  l'm okay. - No,  this is serious.
- 真的 我没事 - 不 你伤得挺重
For God's sake, you can't keep taking these chances.
老天啊 你不能一直冒险
- l'll be fine. - You're bleeding out of your head.
- 我没事 - 你脑袋在流血啊
- lt's gone all sticky. lt'll stop. - You need to be admitted.
- 都开始发粘了 一会就不流了 - 你得住院
No. You know how much l hate that. lt takes forever.
不 我很讨厌这样 没个完
- Don't fight me this time. - l'll be all right. lt's just- -
- 听我一次吧 - 我没事 我只是...
l'm missing something. lt's really important.
我丢了样很重要的东西
- Do you know where you are? - Sure.
- 你知道自己在哪吗? - 当然
- What city? - Central City,  U.S.A.
- 哪个城市? - 美国 中央市
What year is it?
今年是哪一年?
This year.
就是今年
- Do you know who you are? - The Spirit.
- 你知道自己是谁吗? - 我是魂
- l beat up bad guys. - And sometimes they beat you up.
- 我打败恶人 - 有时候是他们打败你
And it really hurts when that happens, but l always get better.
那确实很痛 但只会让我变得更强
l don't know why. You don't know why. But The Octopus knows something.
你我都不知道原因 但章鱼似乎知道些什么
Why do you say that?
怎么会说起这个?
Because he told me he knows something.
因为他告诉我的
- You're delirious. Come on. - No.
- 你混乱了 跟我来 - 不
Oh,  golly,  will you look at that.
天啊 过来看看
That was close,  buddy.
你在这呢 伙计
l was looking all over for you.
我找你好半天了
There. That's better.
感觉好多了
Yup. That's better.
好多了
That tears it.
疯掉了
You're delusional.
你精神错乱了
- Tuska,  over here! - Ellen!
- Tuska 过来! - Ellen!
Dr. Ellen Dolan! Over here,  right now!
Dolan医生! 马上过来!
l can hear fluid in his chest.
他胸腔有积液
lt's faint,  but l swear it's there.
虽然不是很明显 但一定没错
l got it. He's got blood in both his lungs.
我明白了 他双肺出血
Stabilize him,  get him on Pegasus.
把他抬上飞机 抬稳了
- Go back to the helicopter. - l'll flip him over.
- 回直升飞机上去 - 我帮他翻个身
No,  leave him flat. Get me new gloves. Gauze.
不 让他平躺着 给我拿双新手套 还有纱布
Hurry it up. lf you can't move any faster, l'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
快点 如果你动作不麻利点 我就叫你走人
- You find anything? - No,  sir.
- 有什么发现么? - 没有 长官
l'm just feeling dizzy from all the action,  l guess.
我只是折腾得有些晕
- Yeah,  we're all damn impressed. - Thanks.
- 可以理解 确实有些骇人 - 谢谢
You're doing this town no good with your hot-dogging.
你这么炫 对这座城市可没啥好处
- l don't follow you. - We're flat on our asses...
- 你说什么... - 我们他妈的都快累死了...
...happy to clean up after your dog- and- pony show.
...在你耍完帅后 收拾烂摊子的总是我们
Not this again. You know the score.
又来了 你也清楚状况的
l thought l did. Go ahead and enlighten me.
我不清楚 你是倒教教我啊
Bring me up to speed.
让我也熟悉熟悉
Sussman wanted things kept quiet. Leave it at that.
Sussman不想打草惊蛇 别声张了
He thinks l don't run a tight ship?
他觉得我嘴不严实么?
Suspected a leak in your department. Didn't want The Octopus getting away.
他怀疑你的人走漏消息 他不想让章鱼逃了
So you're lnternal Affairs now,  huh? l must have missed that memo.
你什么时候成了内部的人了 我咋不记得了?
Come on,  it was a judgment call. l gave it my best shot.
这只是个猜测而已 我也已经尽力了
l got one officer an inch from dying, another,  his head yanked off...
你搞砸了 我的一个警官差点挂掉 另一个差点被爆头...
...because you went off half- cocked after The Octopus.
...都是你准备不足 就想抓章鱼
You're damn right l'm going after The Octopus!
太他妈对了 我就是要抓他! 每案都是
And you're going through my men like toilet paper.
你就像用厕纸一样消耗我的人手 太过分了!
You been to Dropsie Avenue and C?
你去过Dropsie大道和C区吗?
- Have you seen those girls? - Yeah.
- 你见过那些女孩吗? - 当然
Some just learning how to ride a bike, there they are,  selling their souls...
她们有些才刚学会骑车 就在出卖自己的灵魂...
...slaves to The Octopus and his poison.
...日日夜夜被章鱼荼毒 奴役
Maybe you and your force could use a little obsession,  Dolan.
你和你的手下该用用脑子了 Dolan
could work a little harder.
也许你们应该更尽责一些
Ellen's right. You're off your rocker, talking about cops like that.
Ellen说得对 你疯了 竟这样评价警察
Maybe if you and your force could find The Octopus...
如果你们能找到章鱼的话...
- ...l wouldn't have to play it solo. - Solo,  huh?
- ...我也不用单打独斗了 - 单打独斗?
Solo?
单打独斗?
That wasn't our deal,  hotshot.
我们说好的可非如此 自大狂
Well,  then maybe we don't have a deal anymore,  commissioner.
可能那些都是过去的事了 长官
Why,  you....
你...
You're living at the edge of a cliff,  son.
你正站在悬崖的边缘 孩子
And all you got is a tired old man trying to hold you back.
只有一个疲惫的老人在拉着你
Look,  we're both tired.
听着 我们都很疲惫
Yeah.
是的
- Yeah. - Just give me 1 0 minutes.
- 是的 - 给我10分钟时间
Hell,  l don't know why l even bother to try and talk to you anymore.
靠 我不知道自己为啥 还要在你身上浪费时间
Just give me 1 0 minutes.
给我10分钟时间
Just to clear my head.
让我清醒一下
Right. Sure.
好吧
What's 1 0 minutes in a man's life anyway?
10分钟在一个人的生命中 能算什么?
Spirit?
魂?
Sir.
长官
That cliff l was talking about?
我所说的悬崖
There's no bottom.
下面深不见底
Don't jump.
别跳
''What are you?'' That's what the woman asked me.
"你是什么?" 那女人问我
It's a good question.
问得好
I wish I had an answer for her.
我希望自己能回答这个问题
Am I a crazy man?
我是个疯子吗?
Or am I a man at all?
我还算是人吗?
Some nights,  like this one...
许多个夜晚 就像今晚一样...
...when the wind bites deep, bone deep...
...当寒风刺骨之时...
...and even my city seems to leave me behind,  I wonder:
...当城市似乎将我抛弃之时 我在思考
Am I some sort of ghost?
我是幽灵吗?
Some sort of Flying Dutchman?
就像 "漂泊的荷兰人"? (传说中无法靠岸的幽灵船)
If the wind picked up hard enough...
如果风吹得太厉害...
...would I just blow away?
...我是否也会随风而去?
I'm not a cop.
我不是警察
Not anymore.
不再是了
Not even a dead man.
甚至不是死人
Not even a spirit.
不再是魂
We made it,  boss. Just like you said we would.
我们成功啦 老大 就像你所说的那样
You still here?
你还在啊?
Of course l'm still here. l'm your trigger. l blowed holes right through The Spirit.
我当然在 我就是你的扳机 我在魂身上打穿了几个洞哦
You're a trigger,  Pathos.
你是个扳机 Pathos
Just look at you.
看看你吧
Quick Draw McGraw himself.
活脱脱一个"快枪麦克劳" (美国50年代动画片角色)
l'll be great. l don't have any bones sticking out.
我没事 骨头都没露出来呢
A couple of splints,  l'll be good to go.
夹上夹板 我又活蹦乱跳了
Yeah,  just hop right over to St. Alice's, get fixed up all nice and new.
没错 你去圣爱丽丝医院 养个完好如初
l'll have to explain why a criminal mastermind like myself...
我就得解释一下 为什么像我这样的天才作案专家...
...doesn't provide his employees with medical insurance.
...竟不给他的手下提供医疗保险
That'd be egg on my face,  Pathos.
那让我很丢脸 Pathos
You know l don't like egg on my face.
你知道 我可不喜欢丢脸
- Hadn't thought of that. - No.
- 这我倒没想过 - 没想过?
Using your brain? That,  you weren't built for.
用用脑子吧 噢 你是没脑子的
Just tell me where the emergency room is.
那告诉我急诊室在哪就行了
l'll tell them l'm one of the homelesses. They don't make them pay.
我告诉他们我是个流浪汉 这样就不用付钱了
Homelesses always get hurt. Because it's free.
流浪汉很容易受伤 因为看病不用钱嘛
- That'll work! - So will this.
- 这方法行得通! - 那这样也行
No egg on my face!
别丢我的脸!
Not a glob!
丢一点都不行!
Not a glob.
一点都不行
Any other case,  little buddy.
别的什么案子
Any other job.
什么差事都好
lf it were anyone but her.
为何偏偏是她...
Sand.
Sand
Sand Saref.
Sand Saref
Where's your bike?
你的车呢?
You scrape your knee, or are you scared for a race?
是真的膝盖伤了 还是害怕跟我比赛啊?
No,  l got sick of that stupid bike.
不 我觉得那愚蠢的车子很恶心
You got sick of losing races to me is more like it.
是怕比赛输给我吧
Where'd you put it?
你的车在哪?
l pawned it over at Fellman's.
我到Fellman的店里把车给当了
- l got a few bucks for it. - Pawned it?
- 换了点钱 - 你把车当了?
Look there.
看那个
l bet those are real diamonds.
我打赌那是真钻石
You see how they catch the light, Denny?
看到它们反射的光了么 Denny?
Only real ones do that.
真的钻石才能这样呢
What's with you?
你怎么了?
Nothing much.
没啥
- He's not drinking again,  is he? - No,  no,  he's not drinking.
- 他不会又喝酒了吧 - 不 不是酒的事
What's got you needing money,  then?
那你为什么急着用钱?
Just something that l saw over at the window at Kurtzman's.
我在老K的店里看到了个小东西
ls it a badge,  like my dad's?
是像我老爸那样的警徽吗?
No,  no. lt wasn't a badge.
不是 不是警徽
Good,  you ain't hardly earned a badge.
不错 你没有去买警徽
Well,  it was something that l thought that,  you know...
呃 我觉得...
...you might like seeing as how you like shiny things and all.
...你也许很喜欢闪光的东西
lt opens up too. You can take it and look at the picture.
可以打开的 看看里面的照片吧
lf you don't like it,  old man Kurtzman said he'd take it back.
老K说 如果你不喜欢 可以退货
Do you like it?
喜欢吗?
So you want me to be your girl?
你想我做你女朋友?
Yeah,  sure. l mean,  if- -
是的 我的意思是 如果...
You know,  if it's all the same to you.
如果你也愿意的话
Well,  l suppose l can wear it now and then.
我想 我可以偶尔戴一戴
- But that doesn't make me your girl. - Yeah. Doesn't make....
- 这可不代表我是你女朋友啊 - 对 不代表....
Yeah,  we had us a time,  all right.
对 多好的一段时光
The way only city kids could.
只有城市孩子才能那么玩儿
l love it!
真刺激!
lt says here Heracles himself fought with the Argonauts.
这本书上说大力神跟Argonauts并肩作战 (古希腊寻宝故事)
lmagine Jason and Heracles back- to- back.
想像一下Jason和 大力神背靠背的情形
- Yeah. - Jason gleaming in his Golden Fleece.
- 对啊 - Jason穿着金羊毛 熠熠发光
Yeah. Yeah.
对啊 对
Then everything went right straight to hell.
然后情况急转直下
My Uncle Pete was a has- been fighter.
我叔叔Pete是个过气的拳手
Sand's dad,  a beat cop who was always looking out for dumb old Pete.
Sand的父亲 一位警察 经常照应又傻又老的Pete
Hey,  Pete! What's all this? What's all- - ?
嗨 Pete! 你干嘛呢? 你...
My Uncle Pete did the only thing his punch- battered brain...
我叔叔Pete用他那被打傻的脑袋...
...could tell him to do.
...想到了他能做的唯一一件事儿
Sand got there a few minutes before me.
Sand早我几分钟到的现场
Come on.
走吧
I tried to be strong for both of us.
为了我们俩 我尽力保持坚强
I said some stuff. I can't remember what.
我说了些话 具体我也记不清了
And then that jerk reporter latched onto us.
然后一个混蛋记者缠上我们了
Sol,  l can't miss this.
Sol 这个机会不容错过
So,  kids,  just how does this make you feel?
孩子们 你们此刻什么感觉?
Are you scared?
害怕么?
- We ain't talking,  so leave us alone. - You gotta give me something.
- 我们不想说 别烦我们 - 总要说点什么吧
I'll give you something.
我来给你爆点料吧
I'll give you three words.
就四个字
I hate cops.
我恨警察
Just leave us alone,  will you?
别烦我们 行么?
l know you're heartbroke,  Sand.
我知道你很伤心 Sand
So am l, but you didn't mean what you said.
我也一样伤心 但你刚才说的不是真心的
Leave me alone,  stay away.
别来烦我 离我远点
- Give it a while. - Give it a while?
- 过一阵就好了 - 过一阵?
- What? What,  us? - Well,  yeah,  that's what l mean.
- 什么好了? 咱俩么? - 对 我就是这个意思
So,  sure,  we grow up and we have kids in this sinkhole?
哦 咱们就在这垃圾地方长大 然后抚育子女?
You're just not talking straight.
你说的是气话
And you become a cop just like you always wanted to.
你会如愿以偿地当上警察
Yeah. Yeah,  maybe l do.
对 有可能会的
Yeah,  and then some punched- out drunk of an old boxer shoots you dead?
对 然后再被个 醉醺醺的傻拳手开枪打死?
- Do you think l want that? - lt wasn't Pete!
- 你觉得我喜欢这些么? - 这不是Pete干的!
- lt was that guido,  and you know that. - Who cares?
- 是那个混混干的 你知道的 - 谁在乎呢?
You know what? l don't want your world.
你知道么? 我不要你的世界
l want diamonds, and l want sports cars...
我想戴钻石 我想开跑车...
...and l want long dresses and l want money. And l want lots of it.
...我要穿长裙 我要钱 好多好多的钱
And where are you going to find all that,  Sand?
你上哪儿找这些东西去 Sand?
l'm not gonna find it here. Not in this toilet of a town.
反正在这儿是不可能的 不是在这个垃圾地方
So you're too good for me? You're too good for all of us? ls that it?
那你是说我配不上你? 我们都配不上你? 是吗?
l am too good for you, and l am too good for this dump.
你就是配不上我 这破地方就是配不上我
- l'm going away,  l'm going far away. - All right.
- 我走了 我要远走高飞 - 好吧
l'm gonna go all over the world,  become rich...
我要游遍全世界 变得好有钱...
...and no one is ever gonna know that l came from this hole!
...最后没有人会知道 我来自这个鸟不拉屎的地方!
No one. And l am never coming back.
我再也不回来了
Then do whatever you want,  Sand!
那就随你的便吧 Sand!
l don't care about you neither. l never even wanna see you again!
我也不在乎你 我再也不愿见到你!
l hate you,  Sand.
我恨你 Sand
I never saw her again.
我再也没见过她
Word is she took off for Europe.
有传言说她去了欧洲
l never knew if she was alive or dead.
也不知道她是死是活
Until now.
直到现在
There's only one way this locket ended up in poor Sussman's hand.
这东西在可怜的Sussman手上 只有一种可能
She was there. She was wearing it. She is implicated.
她当时在场 而且还戴着 这事和她有关
lf she's doing business with The Octopus...
如果她跟章鱼博士合作的话...
...then my feelings don't mean a damn.
...可别怪我六亲不认
l must find Sand Saref...
我必须找到Sand Saref...
...and bring her in.
...然后抓住她
My beautiful Sand Saref.
我美丽的Sand Saref
Are you missing something,  my love?
你是不是丢了什么东西 亲爱的?
Nothing important.
不是什么重要的
Just something l lost a long time ago.
只是件很久以前就丢掉的东西
Mark this moment,  all of you.
记住这一时刻 所有人
A new age begins.
新的时代来临了
An age of great deeds.
美好的时代
An age of great power.
强权的时代
Yes.
是的
All mine.
都是我的
The blood of Heracles is mine.
大力神之血是我的
l am sorely disappointed.
我是相当的失望
Which one of you brought me this?
是谁把这个弄来的?
l guess that'd be me.
估计是俺
- On your knees,  then. - Sure thing.
- 那就快跪下 - 必须的
What happened? What went wrong?
怎么回事? 哪里出岔子了?
Nothing went wrong, thanks for asking.
没出什么岔子 但谢谢关心哇
Where's my vase? l'm supposed to have a vase full of blood.
我的花瓶呢? 应该是个盛满血的花瓶
- lt's supposed to be in that box. - Must've been in the other box.
- 应该在那箱子里的 - 那肯定是在另一个箱子里的啦
What other box?
什么另一个箱子?
Must've been in the other box.
那肯定是在另一个箱子里的啦
What other box,  you fart?
什么另一个盒子 你个蠢材?
The one the pretty lady run off with. We was watching.
被靓女带走的那个吧 我们一直盯着呢
Sand Saref.
是Sand Saref
l thought l scared her off with time to spare.
我还以为我震慑住她了呢
What's she doing in Central City, anyway?
她到底来中心市干嘛来了?
lt didn't occur to you doorstops to mention that there was a second box?
你们这帮傻蛋 就没想起 提到另一个箱子的事?
Nope,  but it looked just like this one. We was watching.
没 但是俩长得可像了 我们看着呢 真滴
Seppuku across the stomach, left to right.
你剖腹吧 从左到右
That tickles.
很痒哎
With the sword,  toe cheese.
用刀剖 傻根儿
So Sand Saref has the blood.
那么说血在Sand Saref手上
You know,  you could've offed her and brought back both boxes.
你应该直接做掉她 然后把两个箱子都带回来
That would've simplified things considerably.
要是那样事儿就好办多了
Oh,  l'm supposed to do everything around here?
哦 啥事儿都要我亲力亲为了?
Now,  that'll wake you up.
喔 神清气爽啊
You have to do something about Sand Saref.
你总得想点办法治Sand Saref吧
Don't worry about Sand Saref.
不用担心
That lady's got a thing for the bling.
这女人喜欢穿金戴银
She was after that other box and whatever it is that's inside of it.
她想要那箱子和里边的东西
lt's kind of creepy the way it glows like that.
这么闪闪发光也怪闹心的
So the situation's hardly a debacle.
看来局势还有的救
Sand Saref has the blood of Heracles,  yes.
Sand Saref手上有Heracles之血
But we have what she wants.
但我们手上有她想要的东西
- All right,  you fatheads listening to me? - We sure are,  boss.
- 好吧 你们这帮胖墩儿听着呢么? - 必须的 老板
Find Sand Saref,  find her now. Tell her l have no problem with her.
去找Sand Saref 现在就去 告诉她我跟她没什么过节
She can have her creepy, blingy thingy.
这闪闪发光的闹心玩意给她
Get me that blood.
把血给我带回来
And keep it safe!
这次照看好了!
Spill one drop and l'll turn you all into hamburger.
要是撒了一滴 我就把你们都变成汉堡包
Don't forget about The Spirit. He's someone to contend with.
别忘了魂 还得对付他呢
He's like a piece of gum stuck to the bottom of your shoe that won't let go.
他就跟粘在鞋底的口香糖一样 死缠着你不放
You know what l mean?
明白我的意思?
The kind you step on in the summer that just won't let go.
就是夏天踩上去的死活不撒手的那种
Am l doing this right?
你看我这么剖合适不?
Yeah,  looks good.
还行 不错
l was just wondering, because it really smarts.
我就是不太肯定 挺疼妮
l hate stepping on gum, even in winter.
就是在冬天我都特烦踩上口香糖
Makes you step funny.
走路都走不好
We're gonna kill The Spirit, and we're gonna kill him now.
咱们会干掉魂的 现在就干
Or sometime soon.
早晚的事
He doesn't publish his address.
他的住址可是保密的
We're not going to look for him.
咱们才不去找他
He's gonna come to us. Real soon.
他会来找我们的 很快就会的
You have a plan.
你有计划了
l left the man a clue that will lead him right to us.
我给他留了个能让他找到咱们的线索
Right soon,  l promise.
快了 我保证
What's the hurries,  anyway?
我还真就不明白了 急啥?
lf The Spirit drinks the blood...
如果血让鬼魂喝了...
...if he so much as realizes what it could do to him...
...如果他知道那血会给他 带来怎样的改变...
...what it could turn him into, then we're finished.
那咱们就歇菜了
And because l said so.
还因为 是我的命令
l am a man of my word,  Ms. Saref.
我可是讲信用的 Saref女士
Are you?
是么?
Take the promises you made to your lovely new wife.
就拿你对你那美丽的新婚妻子 所承诺的吧
''Forsaking all others, '' and all that.
"抛弃了他人"之类的
Let's not get personal,  shall we?
咱们对事别对人 行么?
Oh,  we shall.
哦 行啊
l commissioned you to find a certain treasure for me,  Mr. Donenfeld.
我委托你帮我找些宝物 Donenfeld先生
lt was to mark the climax of my career.
那标志着我事业的顶峰
lts crown jewel.
它的皇冠宝石
The lost treasure of the Argonauts.
Argonauts迷失的宝物
And it was even worth me coming back to this horrid city...
为了那宝物 我甚至可以重回这垃圾城市..
...just to touch it.
...就为了能亲手摸一摸
To hold it.
握一握
To have it be mine.
据为己有
The shiny thing to end all shiny things.
它让所有珍宝都黯然失色
And l paid you a fortune for it.
并且 我可是花了大价钱的
And it would've been worth every nickel,  but you screwed me.
本来这买卖是很划算的 但你却把我给耍了
So now we're gonna take every last one of those nickels...
所以 我们要把剩下的每分钱...
...and transfer them into another bunch of accounts.
...转到别的银行账户上去
What on earth are you talking about?
你到底在说些什么?
You're gonna be quite the philanthropist.
你要当一回大慈善家了
Oh,  type the numbers in for him, darling. He seems a tad dyspeptic.
哦 亲爱的 替他把数字输进去 他好像有点接受不了
l'm going to need your password, sweetheart.
我需要密码 亲爱的
All right.
好吧
lt's robin.
密码是robin
R- O- B- l- N. Like the bird.
R-O-B-I-N 就像鸟的名字一样
Or like the kid sidekick.
或者跟孩子的玩伴似得
You know,  the one with the cute little tights and the tight little derriere.
嗯 就是穿紧身裤很可爱的那个 臀臀也很翘
lt's going through.
转账进行中
Transfer complete.
交易成功
Why the devil are you doing this to me?
你们为什么要这么整我?
You sold me out.
你出卖了我
- l didn't have any choice. - lmagine my surprise...
- 我当时也是无奈之举啊 - 想象一下我会有多吃惊...
...when l show up at the drop point and ran smack into The Octopus.
...我在交货地点出现的时候 迎头碰见了章鱼博士
l mean,  what are the odds of that?
我意思是 咋就这么巧呢?
Unless you sold the Argo's treasure twice...
除非你把阿尔戈号上的宝物卖了两次...
...making a perfect ass of yourself.
...把自己搞得纯粹一混蛋 (ass: 混蛋/屁股 亦指自己臀部漂亮)
A perfect ass.
完美的 翘臀
Well,  he didn't give me any choice.
他当时没给我选择的余地
- He's The Octopus,  he threatened my- - - Your family.
- 他可是章鱼啊 他威胁我.... - 你的家人
Take a good look at those pictures.
好好看看这些照片
They'll reach your family and every news service on the planet...
这些照片会到你家人以及 全球的每个新闻机构手上...
...unless you render them irrelevant.
...除非你能洗脱干系
At least die bravely...
至少死的勇敢点吧...
...rodent.
...废物
Hold all calls.
截下所有电话
Excuse me,  got any change?
抱歉打扰下 有零钱么?
What can l say?
我能说啥呢?
Last night you were 20 minutes from the morgue,  and now look at you.
昨天你还气若游丝的 再看看现在的你
Just look at you.
看看你
l'd recommend three days' bed rest, but why waste my breath?
我应该建议你卧床三天 但我还有必要浪费口舌么?
Look who's talking. You take the night off.
瞅瞅 还说我呢 你才该歇一天的
Yeah,  l'm sure Mrs. Mahoney's heart transplant can wait.
对啊 Mahoney的心脏移植手术不用急的
And we might as well just hold off and see if old Spankowitz's liver explodes.
不如我们再等等看 看看老Spankowitz的肝会不会爆掉
You need to have some fun. Put your feet up,  relax.
你真该去玩玩了 歇歇脚 放松一下
Maybe go see a show.
或者去看场演出
What about you,  big man?
那你呢 大家伙?
- What's on your agenda tonight? - Oh,  l don't know.
- 你今晚打算干嘛? - 哦 我也不知道
Things stay quiet, l'd be up for anything.
只要不出乱子 干点什么都行
- Anything? - Sure,  anything.
- 什么都行? - 对 什么都行
Dinner,  movie.
共进晚餐 看场电影
Anything.
什么都行
- So long as things stay quiet? - Yeah.
- 只要不出乱子? - 对
- So long as things stay quiet. - Sure.
- 只要不出乱子 - 好
Like every crook in Central City goes on sabbatical?
就像中心市的罪犯 都去休息了?
Or maybe if l break the rules.
要么我违犯下规定?
l feel like breaking all kinds of rules.
我看规定都犯光了
- Lower the blinds. - They're all down.
- 关上合页窗 - 都关严实了
Oh,  fast hands.
哦 手好快啊
And quiet.
且悄无声息
- And sneaky. - We'll keep things quiet,  all right.
- 还是偷偷摸摸的 - 咱们小点声 好吧
Very,  very quiet.
非常 非常的安静
Keep the mask on. Something tells me it might be better that way.
面具戴着吧 那样让我感觉更棒
Oh,  Ellen,  l lo- -
哦 Ellen 我爱.....
You're in love with every woman you meet,  Mr. Spirit.
只要是你见过的女人 没有你不爱的 魂先生
You say lovely things to all of us...
你跟谁都甜言蜜语的...
...and you mean every word you say. Every time.
...而且每次你说的话都是真真切切
Ellen,  it's only you.
Ellen 我心里只有你
But we don't even know your real name.
但我们甚至不知道你的真名
l'll tell you my name.
我告诉你我的名字
Someday l'd love to do your autopsy.
等你死了 可得让我解剖尸体啊
Oh,  thanks for the thought.
谢谢你能这么想啊
l'd make a fortune.
那我就赚大发了
Spirit! Front and center!
鬼魂! 太嚣张了你!
- He's all yours. Fresh as a daisy. - You should get some sleep.
- 他是您的了 生龙活虎的 - 你真该睡会儿了
- You look like hell. - Love you too,  Daddy.
- 脸色看起来差的不得了 - 我也爱你 老爸
lt's an honor to meet you,  Mr. Spirit. l'm Morgenstern.
非常荣幸认识您 魂先生 我是Morgenstern
Rookie,  fresh from Baltimore.
新手 刚从巴尔的摩调来
Good to have you aboard, Morgenstern.
欢迎加入 Morgenstern
Come on, we haven't got the whole day.
快走吧 时间紧迫
- Dr. Dolan,  l can't thank you enough. - Just doing my job,  sir.
- Dolan医生  感激不尽 - 我应该的 先生
Bastard.
混蛋
- Marry me. - Just doing my job,  sir.
- 能嫁给我么? - 我应该的 先生
And what a job it is.
干的真漂亮
Central City's own masked manhunter.
中心市的蒙面侠
You're worshipped by the kids.
你知道孩子们都崇拜你
Anything you'd care to share with them?
能跟他们说点什么吗?
Play it straight,  youngsters. Don't be too tough on your parents.
要懂事 孩子们 要理解爸爸妈妈
They work hard. And remember...
他们工作很辛苦的 还有记住...
...brush your teeth.
...勤刷牙
Every word a pearl of wisdom.
金玉良言啊
Don't forget to remind them to take their vitamins.
别他妈忘了提醒他们吃维他命
And for the ladies?
跟女士们呢?
You know, we hang on your every word.
我们对您说的可是言听计从
Well,  I don't think I could say anything other than thanks...
嗯 我只想说 谢谢...
...for being such amazing, lovely creatures.
你们每一个都是如此美丽可爱
No two alike.
且独一无二
Jesus!
天啊!
- Ever meet a skirt you didn't chase? - Just trying to be nice.
- 碰到过你不想追的女人么? - 我得礼貌嘛
You've been nice to my daughter.
你跟我女儿可真够礼貌的
When will you break her heart, lounge lizard?
你打算啥时候伤她的心 油嘴滑舌男?
- Lounge lizard? Where do you get off? - l'll call you anything l want.
- 油嘴滑舌男? 怎么这样叫我? - 我想怎么叫就怎么叫
l don't know why l bother talking with you.
我都不知道干嘛还要跟你费口舌
Because we fight crime, and right now we got our hands full.
因为咱们共同打击犯罪 忙的可是不可开交
You noticed,  have you? Thought with all the tail you chase,  you'd forgotten.
哦 你还知道啊? 我还以为 你忙着追美女 早忘了呢
lt's The Octopus.
是章鱼
Again with The Octopus.
又来了 章鱼
He's up to something big and it's got to do with me.
他现在在谋划大案 而且跟我有关
He said some weird stuff about him and me.
他说了些有关我和他的奇怪的话
l gotta find out what he's talking about. lt's important.
我得查查他到底说的什么 这很重要的
Hold it.
先别走
Can we forget about The Octopus for one minute?
能不能先不说章鱼 就一会儿就行?
Just one minute?
就一会儿?
Now,  we got us a hot case and a murder suspect...
现在手里有个棘手的案子 还有个犯罪嫌疑人....
...who's hauling her butt to the airport.
...她正在往机场的路上走
- Her? - Name is Sand Saref.
- 她? - 她叫Sand Saref
- Sand Saref? - Sand Saref.
- Sand Saref? - Sand Saref
- Local girl. - Only picture of her.
- 本地女孩儿 - 我只有她的照片
lt's over 1 5 years old.
这片子有15年了
Father was a cop. Took one in the face.
她父亲是个警察 脸部中枪
Disappeared following her father's murder- -
在她父亲被杀之后就消失了
Told some snoop reporter that she hated cops.
她跟个垃圾记者说她恨警察
- Right on TV,  she said she hated cops. - She hated cops.
- 就在电视上说的 说她恨警察 - 她恨警察
- That's what l said. - Moved to Europe.
- 我刚才不说了么 靠 - 她去了欧洲
Eight marriages later,  runs every jewelry heist this side of Bulgari.
离过八次婚以后 把保加利亚人所有的珠宝店都抢了
Except for in Central City.
除了中心市的
- She never came back. - You never heard of her.
- 她从没回来过 - 所以你才没听说过她
- You never heard of her,  right? - She never came home.
- 你没听说过她 对吧? - 她从没回来过
You on drugs or something?
你嗑药了还是咋地?
Come on.
走吧
Behind the lines,  folks.
别越线
- Commissioner. - Sand Saref.
- 长官 - Sand Saref
She's overseen hundreds of jewelry robberies...
她策划过上百起珠宝劫案...
...and in not one case was a police officer so much as wounded.
...但却没有一次使警员受伤的
Now,  what are the odds of that,  huh?
你说怎么就这么巧呢 嗯?
Sounds like an Electra complex.
好像是恋父情结
- What's that? - Electra complex. Plain as your face.
- 什么? - 恋父情结 跟你那脸一样简单
Honey,  l'm just an alter cocker.
亲爱的 我就是个老俗人
Give me something to work with.
多给我说说嘛
Old fart.
老糊涂了
Jews today. Can't take time to learn their own language.
现在的犹太人啊 连自己的语言都不学了
Electra complex.
恋父情结
lt's like an Oedipal complex except it's for girls.
跟恋母情结差不多 只不过是针对女孩儿来说的
She doesn't hate cops.
她不恨警察
She's just angry she lost her daddy.
她只是因为失去父亲而生气
Electra complex,  plain and simple.
恋父情结 多直白啊
Damn. This girl's gonna make detective in no time.
靠 这姑娘没几天就能升警探
Thank you,  sir.
谢谢 长官
- You like her new jacket? - Excuse me?
- 你喜欢她的新警服么? - 什么?
You can't take your eyes off the ladies.
装啥啊 孩子 你一看到女人眼睛就拔不出来
There's no chance in hell you haven't noticed Morgenstern's new flak jacket.
你绝不可能没注意到 她的新防弹夹克
- Even if you are on drugs. - l'm not on drugs.
- 就算是你嗑药 也会注意到的 - 我哪儿嗑药了
State of the art,  these jackets.
这些夹克采用的都是现代技术
We had us a shipment of these babies...
我们之前订做了一批
...but we couldn't pay for them until today...
可一直都无力支付 直到今天...
...when we got a very generous private donation to the force.
我们收到了一笔慷慨的私人捐款
One hundred million dollars generous.
一百万美元 慷慨吧
A lot of money.
真是一大笔钱
You're damn straight it is. lt was like a bolt out of the blue.
你说话可真是直率 这笔钱像道闪电似地突如其来
An online donation. Anonymous.
线上捐款 匿名的
Yeah,  sure,  anonymous.
那是自然
Took our brain boys all of an hour to track it right back here.
花了手下的智囊团一个小时 才最终找到了这个地方
To the offices of an expert in ancient artifacts.
这儿是古董专家的办公室
Yeah,  who turned said artifacts into a fortune.
没错 据说靠古董发达了
You might say he was a purveyor of stolen property...
你也许会说他只是替人销赃
...or,  as we put it in the vernacular, a fence.
或者用行话来讲 就是黑商
A world- class fence by the name of Donenfeld.
名叫Donenfeld的世界级黑商
Yeah.
嗯
But quelle surprise,  old Donenfeld, he ain't looking so good.
可令我们吃惊的是 Donenfeld老先生看起来情况不妙
And my good buddy Seth here...
我们这位兄弟 Seth
...he says the old man had a visitor...
他说今天有人来拜访他
...just about the same time he got the hard goodbye.
没过多久他就同这个世界永别了
What did you say her name was again there?
你说她的名字叫什么来着?
Sand. Sand Saref.
叫Sand  Sand Saref
She didn't have an appointment.
她没有预约过
Sand Saref. Some moniker,  huh?
Sand Saref 是个绰号吧?
Yeah,  it's a strange name.
嗯 这名字不常见
- lt's one of a kind. - Yeah.
- 独一无二 - 没错
And my good buddy Seth here...
我在这儿的好兄弟Seth
...he couldn't be bothered to even call it in.
他甚至没有进来看看
My hands were tied,  officer.
我手上都是活儿 长官
Mr. Donenfeld had a standing order.
Donenfeld先生给我下了命令
l was never to come into his office unless he called me in.
除非他叫我进来 否则我永远 不能进他的办公室一步
Never.
不能
Never,  ever,  ever.
永远 不能
Yeah. Sure,  kid.
当然了 孩子
Morgenstern,  get his number.
Morgenstern 记下他的号码
No. Not murder,  not her.
不 不是谋杀 不是她干的
lt's not possible.
这不可能
- So you do know her. - No.
- 这么说 你确实认识她 - 不认识
- lf you're holding back on me.... - l'm not.
- 如果你对我有所隐瞒... - 我没有
Your whole theory, it doesn't make any sense.
你那套说辞 纯属扯淡
Hey,  it fits together like goddamn macrame once you factor in her....
嘿 我说的明明天衣无缝嘛 只要你考虑到她的...
What'd you call it again there?
那玩意儿叫什么来着?
- Electra complex. - Yeah,  that.
- 恋父情节 - 没错 就是那个
lt's psychobabble.
心理分析
Trying to hang a murder rap on that woman...
靠这种不知所谓的心理分析
...over some piece of psychobabble?
就想定一个人的谋杀罪?
Her name is Sand Saref and you know her and you're covering for her.
她叫Sand Saref 你认识她 你在替她掩饰什么
- l never heard of any Sand Saref. - You're lying!
- 我从没听说过什么Sand Saref - 你在说谎!
- Get your hand off my arm,  Dolan. - You're lying to me.
- 松手 Dolan - 你在对我说谎
Let go of my arm before l break yours.
松手 不然我不客气了
Orders,  sir?
长官 有何吩咐?
Tail him.
跟踪他
He's lying.
他在说谎
You did a neat little job up there,  Sand.
Sand 你干得很漂亮
You shouldn't have signed it.
你本该不留痕迹的
Officer Morgenstern,  you wanna help, find me a lead to The Octopus.
Morgenstern警官 如果你想帮忙 就给我找点章鱼的线索吧
l will see it.
我跟
- There. - l'm in.
- 来 - 我跟
And the aces have it.
四条A赢
This l keep as a souvenir.
这个我留作纪念
The rest goes to the man who can get a message to The Octopus.
只要有人能传话给章鱼 其余的就都归他所有了
I thought I was closing in, putting it all together.
我觉得我已渐渐理清了头绪
That three years on, here in my second life...
那之后的三年 我的第二次生命
...I had a pretty good idea of what I had to do.
我十分清楚自己的责任
It all got down to me and The Octopus.
一切都关于我和章鱼
We were headed for a showdown.
必须得摊牌了
I was finally gonna scrub the city clean of him...
我终于能将他从这座城市中抹去
...once and for all.
一劳永逸
It wasn't pretty but it was simple enough.
并不轻松 不过够简单
Then you come along like a sack of rocks to my face.
而之后你却神不知鬼不觉地出现了
What's the story,  Sand? What the heck is going on?
到底怎么回事 Sand? 究竟发生了什么?
All night,  I've been rolling it around in my skull.
我的脑海里整晚都是这件事
You and The Octopus? You and murder?
你和章鱼? 你和凶手?
Dolan's gotta be wrong.
Dolan一定弄错了
There's gotta be more to this, some explanation.
肯定另有隐情 解释这一切
Not murder,  not you.
你不是凶手 与你无关
Can't believe that about you.
真不能相信是你干的
You were tough,  Sand, on the outside...
Sand 你外表冷漠
...but inside,  you were warm.
但内心却十分热情
And soft.
温柔
All woman.
地道的女人
One thing I'd bet my bottom dollar on:
我敢用口袋里的最后一块钱打赌
You wouldn't be caught dead hiding out in a fleabag...
你不会像普通的罪犯那样
...like any ordinary criminal would. No.
裹着睡袋横尸郊野 不会的
No,  your taste was always first- class.
不会的 你的品位永远一流
All the way.
一直如此
Weird.
奇怪
That's just plain damn weird.
真他妈的怪
Sir,  you promised the new hyper- addictive synapse accelerant...
先生 你过说新的高成瘾性 神经键促进剂
...would be ready by last week.
上周就能配置完毕了
Don't you think that's plain damn weird?
你不觉得这很奇怪吗?
Yes,  sir. Just plain damn weird.
是的 先生 十分奇怪
Also,  our profits are down 20 percent.
还有 我们的利润下滑了20个百分点
Good. l was beginning to think it was just me.
好的 我还以为只有我这么看
That's plain damn weird.
真是奇怪
Yes,  sir.
是的 先生
l was trying to make us a smart one...
我本来想造一个聪明点的
...and this thing just sort of popped out.
可这玩意儿突然蹦了出来
Twenty percent across the board.
满盘皆输 20个百分点
Reduce the price on the old stuff, we'll make it up in units.
给旧货降降价 薄利多销
Word has hit the streets about the side effects.
已经有人在谈及它的副作用了
No one likes having their teeth turned into graham crackers.
没人喜欢自己的牙齿变成全麦饼干
How can l get anything done with all this time on my hands?
只有这么点儿时间 我怎么干得完?
Besides,  when my buddies here find Sand Saref...
况且 只要我的人找到Sand Saref
...l won't need profits, l'll have the blood.
我就不需要什么利润了 有血就足够了
Then if l want something, l'll just take it.
然后我就可以为所欲为了
That's what gods do.
和上帝没什么分别
He is really damn little.
他真是小得可以
l mean...
我是说...
...it's really little.
真的很小
- They can't find her. - Yeah,  we can't find her.
- 他们找不到她 - 嗯 我们找不到她
- We looked everywhere. - Except where she was.
- 我们哪儿都找遍了 - 除了她的藏身之处
- We should've looked there. - We did look.
- 我们该去那儿找找的 - 我们确实找过了
- Where's that? - Kill them all,  please.
- 在哪儿呢? - 把他们都干掉 求你了
Just kill them all.
把他们都干掉
We can't spare them.
能省就省吧
- We're running low. - Yeah.
- 我们已经没多少钱了 - 没错
- You're running low on us. - Floss said so.
- 你们已经没多少钱了 - Floss说的
We was listening.
我们听着呢
l'm depressed.
真是不爽
l wish The Spirit would come so l could get me some real killing done.
魂来了该有多好 我就能真真正正地杀个人了
l told you already, that's going to be complex.
都跟你说了 事情没这么简单
Spirit thinks he can't stay hurt.
魂认为自己不能受伤
That stuff l put in him and me is unstable.
我放在我和他体内的东西并不稳定
Might not last.
长不了了
The blood will take care of that.
有血就万事大吉了
Meanwhile,  l'm getting El Espirito dead while l still can.
与此同时 我要在还有能力的时候 把魂给干掉
To that end...
到那个时候
...l got us another opinion.
我又有主意了
Brought in a specialist.
找个专业人士
Someone to seal the deal.
把这件事摆平
You speak to my soul,  monsieur.
实不相瞒 先生
The black- eyed Venus is in Suite 1 51 0.
那位黑眼睛的美人在1510套房
Long time no see,  Sand.
好久不见 Sand
You gonna arrest me? Or do you have something else in mind?
你要逮捕我? 还是另有所图?
l'm bringing you in.
我要带你走
Hands behind your head.
把手举高 放在脑后
You sure about that?
你确定?
Don't make me repeat myself.
别让我说第二遍
Hands behind your head.
把手举高 放在脑后
Your wish is my command.
悉听尊便
Okay.
好
Put a robe on or something but no tricks.
穿个袍子什么的 不过别耍花招
Yes,  sir,  Mr. Spirit,  sir.
遵命 魂先生
Oh,  watch out for my husband, you'll trip.
噢 当心我的丈夫 不要被绊倒了
Why this?
这是怎么回事?
lt's not like l killed him. He did it to himself about an hour ago.
不是我杀的 一个小时以前他自行解决的
lt's all the fault of this goddamned vase.
都是这个该死的花瓶闹的
He tasted the stuff and,  well,  see for yourself.
他尝了尝里头的东西 就成这样了
- lt's stolen. - Oh,  yeah.
- 是偷来的吧 - 是啊
You are a common criminal.
你是个普通刑事犯
There's nothing common about me.
我身上可没什么普通的
You're a criminal. l'm bringing you in for the murder of a fence,  Donenfeld.
你是个罪犯 我现在以谋杀 Donenfeld黑商的罪名逮捕你
lf you're gonna lock me up...
如果你要把我拷起来
...do it over something l am actually guilty of,  stupid.
得有个实际的罪名 傻冒
Oh,  you're guilty of a lot.
你犯下的罪不计其数
l could burn a priest's ears confessing the half of it.
要忏悔的话 牧师听到一半 耳朵就得冒火
But this time,  my hands are clean, crime fighter.
不过这次我是清白的 正义战士
So run on home, wait for the forensics report.
那就回家等法院的报告吧
l haven't shot anybody in days.
我已经好几天没杀人了
There probably isn't a law on the books that you wouldn't break.
法典上哪条法律你没触犯过
Do l look like a good girl?
我看上去像是个乖乖女吗?
You don't care who you've hurt?
你不在乎自己伤害了谁?
What's that got to do with anything?
什么意思?
Sand,  The Octopus,  that fence and you?
Sand 章鱼 那个黑商 还有你?
Now,  after all of these....
经过这一切以后
Nothing fits together.
完全没有头绪
There's that crazy talk from The Octopus about him and- -
章鱼跟我说过一个很疯狂的故事
Listen,  mister...
听着 先生
...l don't care.
我不在乎
l don't even care about people that l like and l don't know you.
我甚至不在乎自己喜欢的人 而我也不认识你
No,  of course you don't. But things,  now,  those you care about.
你当然不了 不过想想你在乎的那些东西
l don't see what use l could possibly be to you.
我不知道自己对你有何用处
l have nothing to offer this rotten little town of yours.
我没什么能贡献给这个腐坏的小镇
As a matter of fact,  l despise it.
事实上 我鄙视它
There's one thing between that river and that ocean that l came here for.
我远渡重洋来到这里只为了一样东西
What? That stupid vase?
什么? 那个破花瓶?
lt wasn't supposed to be a vase.
不该是个花瓶的
lt was supposed to be worth something more than jewels.
本该是比珠宝更值钱的东西
Something a little girl's dreams are made of.
小女孩儿梦寐以求的东西
l knew a little girl like that once.
我以前认识一个那样的小女孩
You don't know anything. Get out.
你什么都不知道 给我滚
She was a very sweet girl but the world broke her heart.
她是个很可人的女孩儿 可是这个世界伤了她的心
She wasn't after any vase.
她要的不是什么花瓶
She was looking for a hero. Weren't you,  little girl?
她要的是个英雄 不是吗 小女孩?
You were looking for a hero and his armor.
你在找寻一位英雄和 他神话中的盔甲
The only man who would know that is dead.
唯一知道这些的人已经死了
The Fleece. The Golden Fleece.
羊毛 金羊毛
Jason's Golden Fleece.
Jason的金羊毛
He's dead. You're dead. You're dead.
他死了 你死了 你已经死了!
- Will you look at that? - Don't that beat all?
- 瞧啊 - 他不是见谁灭谁么?
Hey,  it's The Spirit.
嘿 是魂啊
- He's street pizza. - He looks stupid.
- 垃圾 - 他看上去蠢死了
- Wanker. - You'll believe a man can't fly.
- 傻逼 - 相信了吧 人哪儿会飞啊
Jump already.
跳啊
Jump,  jump,  jump
跳 跳 跳
Get me the hell out of here.
带我离开这鬼地方
Not right now. l'm kind of busy.
现在不行 我有点忙
lt's Morgenstern. l might have a lead for you.
我是Morgenstern 我可能有线索
Nobody noticed all of that salt.
居然没人注意到那些盐
lt was right under our noses.
就在我们眼皮底下
- Could you pick up the pace? - Salt. lndustrial salt.
- 你能有点逻辑吗? - 盐 工业用盐
One of The Octopus' henchmen, we found him dead near the flats.
我们在泥滩附近 发现了章鱼手下的尸体
Remember where Sussman got shot?
还记得Sussman在哪儿被杀害的么?
lndustrial salt, it was caked all over his shoes.
他鞋子上都是工业用盐
Dolan was right. you'll make detective in no time.
Dolan说得没错 你马上就能成升警探了
Thank you,  sir.
多谢夸奖
l gotta go.
我得挂了
l'll buy you a drink.
我请你喝一杯
All right,  folks,  show's over. Time to move on.
大伙儿 表演结束了 该走了
Yeah,  well,  Sand, that went great,  didn't it?
Sand 正中你的下怀 对不?
Reunions between old sweethearts will have to wait.
老情人重聚得先放一放了
l got bigger fish to fry. l'm coming after you,  Octopus...
我还有更大的鱼要钓 章鱼 我这就来找你了
...but before l kill you,  you're gonna answer me some questions.
不过在我干掉你之前 你得回答我几个问题
Morgenstern said there was salt on his shoes. There's plenty of it here.
Morgenstern说他鞋子上有盐 这里到处都是盐
Plenty of bad guys too.
到处都是坏人
All the enemy has is guns and knives.
这些家伙手里只有刀枪而已
I have an entire city as my weapon.
整个城市都可以作为我的武器
My arsenal:
我的兵工厂
Iron- jawed fire escapes.
铁制的逃生楼梯
Man- made lightning.
人造闪电
Unforgiving pavement.
人行道也饶不了你们
She provides for me.
她为我提供一切
She protects me.
她保护着我
She is my mother,  my city is.
她是我的母亲 正是如此
She's a good mother.
一个好母亲
She always shows me the way.
她一直为我领路
What a fine detective.
多棒的侦探啊
You followed the breadcrumbs right to us.
给你点面包屑你就找到我们了
You're not doing anybody good by falling asleep on the job.
上班睡觉对谁都没有益处
So why don't you go home, get yourself some proper rest?
干嘛不回家好好休息一下?
You look like something that the cat dragged in.
你一点精神都没有
So sweet of you to come by,  Daddy.
爸爸 你能过来真好
l was just checking in on Sussman. They wouldn't let me see him. Twits.
我来看看Sussman 顺道就过来了 他们不让我见他 真可笑
Sussman's still in critical, they're trying to save his spine.
Sussman还没脱离危险 他们在尽力保住他的脊柱
Yeah? What's the odds of him walking again?
是吗? 他有多大几率能走路?
Hard to tell.
很难说
Miracles do happen.
不过奇迹确实会发生
Damn Spirit.
该死的魂
- He's over the edge. - Don't go there,  Daddy.
- 他过界了 - 别提这茬 爸爸
- He's a goddamn menace. - He's something the world needs.
- 天煞的威胁 - 天下的救星
He's a hero.
他是个英雄
He's a goddamn menace and my own daughter's in love with him.
我女儿爱上了这个天煞的威胁
He's why you're killing yourself, waiting up.
所以你在这儿作贱自己
Yes. He's why l'm still here tonight.
没错 正因为他我今晚才留在这儿的
Yeah. Just in case they wheel him in here...
是啊 等着那天煞的家伙又一次...
- ...one more goddamn time. - Just in case.
- 被送到这里来 - 有备无患
So you can lose your youth stapling his parts back?
这么说 只为一次次把那家伙拼起来 你就要搭上你的青春了?
l'm not a child. And l rarely use staples on anybody.
我不是小孩子了 我不是对谁都这样的
- Can't you see what you're doing? - l know exactly what l'm doing.
- 你知道自己在做什么吗? - 我再清楚不过
l'm giving him exactly what he needs.
他需要什么 我就给他什么
- He's using you. - He needs me.
- 他在利用你 - 他需要我
l'm the only one who knows his body.
我是唯一了解他身体的人
How to treat him.
知道怎么照顾他
Plenty of dames who know all about his body,  from what l hear.
据我所知 了解他身体的女人多了去了
That's not what l meant.
我不是这个意思
Plenty of broads he's stretched across a gurney or what have you...
在轮床上把那么多女人都迷得...
...knowing just what to say.
他应对自如呢
So this is why you came here tonight.
这才是你此行的目的吧
Melting them like butter with his fingers- -
用手指像抹黄油般把她们融化
That's enough.
够了
Don't make me ask you to leave.
别让我赶你走
Honey,  l don't know how to talk about this stuff.
亲爱的 我不知道这事要如何开口
You surely don't.
你当然不知道
Why do you think l spend my nights knocking around that house all alone?
你觉得我每天晚上一个人 在那屋子里转悠是为了什么?
Guess she had her reasons.
我想她总有自己的苦衷吧
You're married to your job.
你太爱你的工作了
So am l.
我也是
So is he.
他也是
You were so much happier in the old days with Denny.
以前和Denny一起的时候你快乐多了
Denny's dead.
Denny死了
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah,  Denny Colt is dead.
Denny Colt死了
- Sweet kid. - Yes,  he was.
- 多好的孩子 - 是啊
And l'll never forget him but we keep going.
我永远也不会忘了他 可生活还得继续
l lost my Boy Scout.
我的阳光男孩啊
Yeah. Yeah...
是 是...
...and l lost my little prom queen,  huh?
我的舞会皇后也不再了 是吧?
- Good night,  sweetheart. - Good night,  Daddy.
- 晚安 亲爱的 - 晚安 爸爸
l just hope that son of a bitch knows how lucky he is.
但愿那兔崽子知道自己有多幸运
He doesn't.
他不知道
I can feel you.
我能感觉到你
You're so weary.
你太疲倦了
Let me hold you.
让我抱着你吧
What smells dental?
牙齿的味道?
Dental and Nazi.
牙齿和纳粹
Great.
太好了
Oh,  no.
噢 不
Oh,  brother.
噢 拜托
l've known some pretty strange women in my time,  some darn strange women.
多年来 我见过很多怪女人 其中有些怪异之极
But this one...
可她...
...if she is who l think she is, she's got the final word on strange.
如果她是我想的那样 她才算是"怪"到了底
l am Plaster. Plaster of Paris.
我是plaster paris
l will stick to my man.
我会伴着我的男人
Till death do us part.
直到死亡把我们分开
Death.
死亡
Death. Death,  death.
死亡 死亡 死亡
lt's just about all we think about, isn't it?
这正是我们所思所想 不是吗?
We eat...
我们进食
...so we won't die.
所以不会饿死
We mate so that our seed will live on.
我们交合 所以血脉传承
Create art and build skyscrapers...
我们创作艺术品 建起摩天大楼
...so that our names will be remembered for centuries.
所以芳名流传百世
Mr. Long,  my good friend, how are you?
喂 Long先生 好久不见 还好吧?
What can l do for you?
能为你做些什么?
A message?
口信?
And from whom would that be?
是谁留下的呢?
Sand Saref. Oh,  yes,  l know her.
Sand Saref 噢 对 我认识她
Well,  you should've known better than to play cards with her.
哈哈 别再被骗去和她玩牌了
And what would her message be?
那她想说什么呢?
The projects?
那个计划?
Out off that old main drag,  oh.
就在那条老主街上 噢
Hell,  yeah,  l know it.
噢 肯定 我知道
Tomorrow night,  then.
就明晚吧
Let's say...
具体时间...
...after dinner.
晚饭后吧
Zai jian,  my honored friend.
再见 亲爱的朋友
- Where was l? - Death.
- 我说到哪儿了? - 死亡
Death,  yes.
死亡 对
We live our short...
我们的生命 如此短暂...
...frantic,  fearful lives, twisting this way and that.
疯狂与恐怖 还要承受这样或那样的苦恼
Music and ambition.
伴着音乐和雄心
Making up gods,  afterlives, all to keep our eyes off...
我们打造出众神与来世 想去无视...
...that immovable,  impassable, diamond- hard retaining wall...
那坚固而无法逾越的 硬如钻石的壁障
...that is death, realizing it will splatter our brains...
死亡 一想到它 我们就会极度地...
...like eggs.
沮丧
Pardon me, but is there a point to all this?
不好意思 你到底想说什么?
Because l'm getting old just listening to you.
听你嗦 我头都白了
Man,  you are really thick.
伙计 你真不明就里
You just don't get it.
你还是不明白
We're two of a kind,  you and me.
我们俩是同类 你和我
Ain't neither one of us getting old.
我们谁都不会变老
Well,  l sure as heck can get bored.
够了吧 我开始厌烦了
You keep teasing about how we're two of a kind.
你不断标榜我俩是同类
So how's that?
那到底是什么?
What are we,  Octopus?
我们是什么 章鱼?
l'm getting to that.
我正准备告诉你
Well,  move it along.
行 那就快说
Do you remember your death, pretty boy?
还记得自己的死吧 帅哥?
Not the sort of thing a guy forgets.
这种事肯定忘不了吧
Yeah,  l remember.
对 我记得
When they wheeled you in, you were stone- cold dead.
他们送你过来的时候 你骨头都凉了
Not a breath of life in you.
没有半点呼吸
You were perfect.
死得很完美
Dead as Star Trek.
好似从未活过一般
And I was your coroner.
我负责验你的尸
But I was,  oh,  so much,  much more than that.
但我 噢 远远不只是一个验尸官
l'd built up a righteous drug trade.
我建立了一张绝好的贩药网
lt's amazing how much a hospital doesn't miss.
医院没记录的药多得让人发指
All you have to do is water it down, spruce it up and achtung.
只需要兑点水 包装好 然后就能致敬了
Swiss bank accounts.
向瑞士银行致敬
But mere money was never what The Octopus was after.
但章鱼的追求绝不是这点钱
All right,  so l give up. What were you after?
好吧 我猜不出了 你追求的是什么?
lmmortality.
长生不老
All five sweet syllables of it.
就这四个动听的字
There had to be a better way to keep someone alive...
肯定有更好的方式让人们活着
...other than cutting them open like some free- range chicken.
而非处理放养鸡那样 把他们切开了事
Free- range chickens with their big, brown,  ugly- ass eggs.
那些鸡下的棕色的蛋 硕大而丑陋
They piss me off.
让我非常不爽
Every time l think about those big, brown eggs,  they piss me off.
每次我一想到那些硕大 棕色的东西 我就会发毛
Or pills. They're just another way to stall death.
又或是吃药 另一种延缓死亡的办法
Cling on for a heartbeat. Hardly the answer.
暂且偷生 基本没用
- l got down to basics. - The essence of life.
- 我要掌握本质 - 生命的本质
- l cracked code. - Genetics.
- 我破译了密码 - 基因密码
- That's how smart l am. - Yeah,  you're a real smart fella.
- 我就是如此聪明 - 嗯 你确实很聪明
Thank you. But it wasn't that easy.
谢谢 但接下来并不顺利
And l've got a freezer full of stray beagles to prove it.
我用一冷柜无主的小狗来做实验
Oh,  what that serum did to those poor dogs...
噢 血清在可怜狗狗身上的反应
...was just plain wrong.
完全不对劲
But when l got it right, well,  l had to try it out.
但若要成功 就必须继续试验
l wasn't about to try it on myself. l might've come out looking funny.
但不能对自己做 否则可能不成人样
l needed a human.
我需要一个人类
And there l was.
刚好遇到了我
And there you was.
刚好遇到了你
l gave you a modest injection and l waited.
给你注射适量血清后 我就等着
Your second life began that very night.
而你就在那一夜获得了重生
Do you remember?
还记得吧?
Oh,  yeah,  l remember.
噢 是的 我记得
Somewhere in the midst of all that praying...
一个弥漫着祈祷 呜咽
...and whimpering and sniveling...
和哭泣的地方
...you must have found something sharp.
你肯定找到了个利器
You know,  l always wanted to ask:
但是 我一直很好奇:
Where did you go when you got out?
你出来后去哪儿了?
l took a walk.
我四处走了走
I had myself a think.
独自想了一会儿
I visited an old friend.
去见了位老朋友
l don't know what happened, but l still move,  l still breathe.
我不知道怎么回事 但我还在动 还在呼吸
lt's impossible,  but l'm still alive.
虽然不可能 但我的确还活着
All my life,  all l wanted to be was a good cop.
我从小的夙愿就是做个好警察
That's all changed. Everything's changed.
事情已变了 所有都变了
They're winning,  sir. The bad guys are winning.
他们快赢了 长官 坏人快赢了
l think l've got something more to fight back with now.
但我现在拥有了更多筹码来反击
l'm something else now.
我现在 与众不同了
l can go places,  l can do things they won't let cops do.
我可以触及警察不能做的灰色任务
But l can't have any weaknesses. No name. No friends.
但我不能有把柄 不能有名字和朋友
l have to stay dead in everybody's eyes.
必须让人们以为我死了
Even Ellen's.
包括 Ellen
But l could be your spy.
我可以做你的探子
l could work with your men.
我能和你的人一起做事
Behind them,  in the shadows.
在他们身后 看不见的地方
l could be the city's protector,  its- -  lts- -
我可以做这城市的保护者 她的... 她的...
lts spirit. yexunadoushi
她的鬼
Exit hero cop,  enter The Spirit.
不做英雄警察 转行做鬼魂
Pain in the ass. Tough as nails.
尽惹麻烦又难对付
Eureka!
成功啦!
So l shot myself up,  and we became brothers under the skin.
我也给了自己一枪 就成了你真正的兄弟
So,  what the hell are we,  Octopus?
那我们到底是什么 章鱼?
You're works in progress.
你是尚待改进的作品
And once he has the vase and its contents...
等他得到那个花瓶和里面的东西
...its mystic contents, lost over millennia...
那些神秘的 已失踪数千年的东西
...he'll drink of it and he'll become immortal.
他会喝掉 并从此长生不老
Don't tease.
别唬人了
Seeing as how l'm gonna die anyway, clue me in.
看在我肯定会死的份上 说下去
What's in the vase?
花瓶里装的什么?
- Thor's hammer? - No.
- 雷神之锤? - 不是
Better.
更好的
The DNA...
是神的...
- ...of a god. - Not a god. Not exactly.
- 基因 - 严格说 不是一个神
Yeah,  because,  you know,  humans and gods,  well,  they don't mix very well.
嗯 因为 人和神 嗯 大家没个准确的概念
The only route to take is to find the connection between man and god...
唯一辨别是人或神的办法只有 看看他们
...the child of an immortal and a human.
是神还是人生的
See,  Zeus couldn't keep it in his pants, so he made bags and bags of heroes.
看吧 宙斯把持不住自己 所以造就了一批又一批的英雄
Now,  the greatest of them all was Heracles.
最伟大的当属大力神
And we found his ass.
而我们找到他了
Well,  his blood anyway. He left some blood around.
噢 他的血而已 他在某处流了点血
And we know where it is.
我们找到了
So that's the missing link between science and magic.
这就是在科学与魔法之间 那一失踪的纽带
Now,  once Heracles' blood mixes with Octopus' formula....
当大力神的血与章鱼的制剂混合后
- l become a god. - Or the next best thing.
- 我就是神了 - 或者另一件好事
l become a god.
我变成了神
And you'll be just one more sad little byproduct.
你成了件失败的副产品
One of his many,  many,  many failures.
他的众多失败作品之一
Come on,  now. Rome wasn't built in a day.
行了吧 罗马不是一天建成的
Besides,  look at all the lovely buddies l've made along the way.
另外 看看这样做出来的可爱家伙
We was easy to make.
我们很容易做
Yeah,  the boss says we was easy to make.
是的 老大说我们很容易做
But your failures were several.
但在你身上 已失败许多次了
And unpleasant.
这很讨厌
Yeah,  you know, you get so much as one little drop...
只用了一滴 就做出了这么多个
...the wrong temperature, and everything just- -
而且温度也不对 各种条件都...
Let me show you.
给你看看吧
lt's kind of sad...
会让人难过
...but it's really kind of cool too.
但也同样很酷
This is Muffin.
这是 Muffin
She's my favorite.
我的最爱
We have to have people over more often.
我们必须多做点人
l like this.
我喜欢这个
The cat.
小猫
She is all the reason l need.
我就是在等待这个理由
l will kill you.
让我决心杀了你
- Oh,  no,  you have to die,  Spirit. - Yeah,  because you got the juice,  man.
- 噢 不 你必须死 魂 - 对 因为你体内有试剂
Your system's been prepared. You're the only one the blood won't kill.
你身体机能已精心布置 你是唯一不会被大力神之血杀死的人
One sip and you could be rendered as immortal as he.
只要喝一小口 你可以和他 同样长生不老了
The Octopus can be the only one.
但只有章鱼一人得以永生
There can be no competition once he's world ruler.
在他统治世界后不能有对手
Yes,  then everyone will have to do what l say.
对 每个人都必须听从我的命令
They will all have to do what l say because l will be the ruler of the world.
他们都必须服从我 因为我才是这个世界统治者
Then everything will start to make sense.
那样 事情才会变得合理
Yes,  everything will make sense.
是的 每件事都会合理
Everything will start to make sense.
每件事都会变得合理
Let's get back to business.
我们还是做正事吧
Yes,  back to business.
好 做正事
Back to killing your ass.
宰你的事
Now,  here's where things become a little tricky.
现在有点小麻烦了
lt's all about integration.
都是因为愈合
Now,  in your current state, you heal very quickly.
目前 你的情况是 能快速自愈
Your wounds mend in moments.
你的伤口会瞬间修复
The only solution,  it turns out,  is to affect your systemic disintegration.
唯一的办法是 扼制你的系统愈合功能
ln short...
简言之...
...to render you into so many different parts spread so far...
把你碎尸为这几段后
...that reintegration would be impossible.
愈合就无法实现了
And being the man that l am...
而作为我这样的人
...l like to start from the bottom and work my way up.
我喜欢从脚底开始 按我的方式向上进行
Floss,  bring me those bags.
Floss 把袋子给我
l'm going to mail your ass all over the country.
我会把你寄往全国各地
Plaster...
石膏
...bring me his toes.
把他脚趾头切下来
Plaster.
Plaster
Enough of this frog talk.
别再说这鸟语了
l don't understand it.
我听不懂
Paris...
Paris
...give me his toes.
把他脚趾头给我切了
That's an order.
这是命令
l hate you.
我恨你
This is for Sand.
这是为了Sand
This is for me.
这是为了我
And this one's for Muffin.
而这是 为了Muffin
That all you got?
就这两下子?
Who is this Sand?
那个Sand是谁?
Not now. Let's go.
待会吧 先出去
The Spirit.
鬼魂
Plaster.
Plaster
And this is for Sand.
这是为了Sand
l am Plaster of Paris.
我是 Plaster
The toast of Montmartre.
来自蒙马特尔
l will stick to my man.
我会伴着我的男人
Till death do us part.
直到死亡把我们分开
You're close now.
你快了
Very,  very close.
很快 很快了
You can't fight me.
你无法抗拒我
You. You are mine. Mine. Mine.
你 你是我的 我的
Hey,  man,  l know the feeling.
嘿 朋友 我知道这感觉
You should meet my wife.
你该见见我老婆
Just put one foot in front of the other.
只需把一只脚放到另一只前面
Here we go again.
呃 又来了
I'm dead again.
我又死了
The fight's gone out of me.
我不想抗拒了
I'm ready for you,  Lorelei.
我来了 Lorelei
Come.
来吧
Come. Come. Come.
来吧 来吧 来吧
It is time.
时候到了
Come. Come.
来吧 来吧
No more pain.
不再有痛苦
No more suffering.
不再受煎熬
Give up the last of it,  Denny.
放弃那最后的抵抗吧 Denny
Give up the ghost.
放弃做鬼
Give up the spirit.
放弃做鬼魂
Yes,  my darling. Yes.
是的 亲爱的 是的
No.
不
It is done.
结束了
It is done. It is done.
结束了 结束了
What's it they say about when you die...
是谁说人死的时候
...about your whole life flashing before your eyes?
眼前会回闪一生?
Forget all that.
得了吧
All I see are women.
我只看见女人
My sweet Ellen,  always there to put my ragged pieces back together.
亲爱的Ellen 总能把我缝合的完好如初
And Sand.
还有 Sand
That poor lost soul.
那只堕落 迷途的灵魂
Beautiful,  beautiful Sand.
美丽之极的 Sand
It's so funny my last thought would be of Sand.
很奇怪我最后想起的是 Sand
No.
不
Lorelei,  you're not for me just yet.
Lorelei 现在你还不属于我
No,  not again.
别 别又这样
They need me. I gotta go back.
他们需要我 我得回去
I will always be with you,  Denny Colt.
我会一直跟着你 Denny Colt
You won't escape me forever.
你逃不出我的手掌心
They need me.
他们需要我
Sand...
Sand
...at the projects.
计划
Octopus.
章鱼的
Pieces.
东西
Pieces of Sand.
Sand 的东西
Pieces of Octopus.
章鱼的东西
You son of a bitch,  Octopus. You're mine.
他妈的 章鱼 我吃定你了
Always with The Octopus.
总离不了章鱼
- Excuse me,  but wasn't he,  like- - ? - Not right now.
- 打扰下 但他应该 好像...? - 现在别问
But three hours with no vitals. Shouldn't he ought to be dead?
但三小时前就没了生命体征 不是应该死了吗?
lt's a long story.
一言难尽
Somebody get me a tie. And it sure as hell better be red.
给我找根领带 必须要他妈的红色
- This time,  you better know your place. - Hold on.
- 好了 这回你最好弄清身份 - 打住
You're supposed to be my spy, not some vigilante.
你应该是我的探子 而不是他妈的巡警
lf you go all cowboy on me again, l am gonna blast you in half myself.
如果你再不听我的 我他妈亲自把你炸成两截
- You got that? - l got an idea.
- 明白没有? - 我有个办法
- l'm atwitter. - No,  it's good.
- 我又不放心了 - 别担心 是好办法
l promise.
我保证
Hey,  you keep that thing pointed at The Octopus.
嘿 你把这玩意儿对着章鱼
When l give you the word, you blow his head off.
听我命令 就打爆他的头
Then it's on with our wedding night, huh,  baby?
然后我们就该进洞房了吧 宝贝?
Yeah,  baby. Our wedding night.
是的 宝贝 我们进洞房
Who the hell are you?
你他妈谁啊?
- You The Octopus' girlfriend? - Oh,  no,  it's not like that.
- 章鱼的女人吗? - 噢 不 不是那样的
- l mean,  this is fun for me. - Fun?
- 因为很有趣 - 有趣?
We show up here, we look fabulous doing it...
我们都来了 漂亮的交易
...we swap things,  then we leave.
先交换东西 再各自走人
- You're looking to get yourself killed. - Would you lighten up?
- 噢 小心别丢了小命 - 你能放松点吗?
- Should we start shooting? - Don't know.
- 我俩可以开枪了吗? - 我不知道
- No shooting. - No shooting,  you polyp.
- 别开枪 - 别开枪 蠢驴
No sign of The Octopus.
没见到章鱼
Hell of a waste of time if he didn't show up.
他要是不来就白忙活了
Whenever he does,  sir, we are locked and loaded.
不管他何时现身 我们随时锁定目标
That cannon could take out the moon, rookie.
这炮能把月亮轰下来 小菜
Sir,  l'm an excellent shot.
长官 我可是神枪手
ls every goddamn woman in this goddamn hellhole...
难道这个鬼地方的所有女人
- ...out of her goddamn mind? - No,  sir,  we're just equipped.
- 都他妈疯了? - 没有 长官 我们只是准备好了
Sweetie,  he's just using you.
甜心 他只是利用你
Sure he is. l run a very lucrative operation and l'm great eye candy.
当然 我操持着赚钱的项目 而且长的又靓
l walk away, l have my Ph.D. all paid for.
之后偶就走人 去读博士 免费的
Fine. Tell lug nuts over there to give me the box.
好吧 叫那傻瓜把箱子给我
And you,  you start that walking.
而你 赶紧走人
As far away from that animal as you possibly can.
躲开那禽兽 越远越好
He will kill you. He kills everything.
他会杀了你的 他是个屠夫
All right,  fine. l just think you're taking this way too seriously,  that's all.
好的 没问题 我只是觉得你 太过紧张了
Give them the vase.
把花瓶给他们
Boss said l start shooting now.
老大要我现在开枪
Get in the truck.
上车
Nobody goes anywhere.
谁都别动
Floss...
Floss
...fetch me that vase,  please.
请把花瓶拿给我
Get in the truck.
快上车
Give me the blood of Heracles,  now.
把大力神的血给我 快
Walk.
快走
Heracles?
大力神?
l always thought it was ''Hercules.''
我一直以为是"大丽神"
You.
是你
Sand,  you found your armor.
Sand 你找到那件盔甲了
Use it.
穿上
What is it with you and women?
你和这女人是什么关系?
Octopus...
章鱼
...you were right.
你是对的
We're mistakes.
我们的出现是个错误
We never should have happened.
我们本不该存在
- Sir,  this is crazy. - Hold your horses.
- 长官 这太疯狂了 - 你别乱动
He doesn't want any cops getting killed.
他不想有警察伤亡
You're not making this easy.
你没把事情变容易
Come on,  kid.
来吧 孩子
lt ends tonight.
今晚会了结的
You got that right.
这句话对了
l'm The Octopus.
我可是章鱼
l got eight of everything.
我的东西都有八个
There's shot to hell.
这枪该上西天了
And shot to hell.
上西天了
And there's just plain ridiculous.
这可真是可笑
Now.
行动
You idiot,  Octopus.
你这头蠢驴 章鱼
All we needed was to flush you and your gunsels out.
我们要把你和喽罗们全部剿灭
Move,  move.
快 快
Give it to him,  boys.
给他点颜色 弟兄们
Commissioner Dolan, your daughter's here.
Dolan 长官 你女儿来了
We need more men over there.
再派点人过去
- Baby,  you don't wanna be here. - You're joking,  right,  Daddy?
- 孩子 你别过去 - 你开什么玩笑 爸爸?
Have you forgotten what l do for a living? He might need me.
你忘了我的职业吗? 他需要我
You'll be in his way, he doesn't want you here.
你会碍他手脚 他不愿你来的
You don't know that.
你不会了解
You don't know him. You don't know a damn thing.
你不了解他 你什么都不了解
Stop her. Pull her back.
拦住她 让她回来
Yes,  sir.
是 长官
Runny eggs.
真是烦
Finally. Yes.
终于拿到了 真好
Yes.
好!
Yeah!
太好了!
Wha- - ?
什...?
Nice investment,  Sand.
防弹衣不错 Sand
Passes its first field test.
通过初步测试了
Let's die.
同归于尽吧
Oh,  God. Oh,  God,  no.
噢 上帝 噢 上帝 不
No. Oh,  God.
别 噢 上帝
Mother.
妈啊
l guess it's time to finally drop your armor,  Sand.
现在先脱掉盔甲吧 Sand
You lost something.
你丢了些东西
Old man Kurtzman said he'd take it back.
老K说 如果你不喜欢 可以退货
Well...
好吧
...maybe l'll wear it now and then.
我想 我可以偶尔戴一下它
But it doesn't mean l'm your girl.
但不代表我就是你的女朋友了
Ellen. Ellen,  are you all right?
Ellen Ellen 你还好吧?
Goodbye,  Sand.
再见 Sand
Goodbye,  Denny.
再见 Denny
Goodbye,  Spirit.
再见 魂
- ls that Saref? - Give me this one,  Dolan.
- 那是 Saref 吗? - 让我处理吧 Dolan
Just let her go.
让她走吧
She saved me. She saved the world.
她救了我 救了整个世界
Yeah,  well, you had something to do with it.
行 行吧 你要来处理了
All right. All right. Just stay out of my face.
好吧 好吧 别再让我见到你
So who the hell was that back there? Who is she?
刚才那个是谁? 她是谁?
Just an old flame.
老情人而已
Yeah,  she looks old.
的确 看起来是很老
- lt's you l love,  baby. With all my heart. - Yeah.
- 我爱的是你 宝贝 一心一意的爱你 - 是吧
Me and every other woman you meet.
和其他你邂逅的女人
You are amazing.
你太棒了
Neat work yourself,  rookie.
你也干得很漂亮 小菜
Bastard.
大混蛋
We start from scratch.
我们从头开始
Who knows what l'll do?
谁知道我想干嘛?
She wakes. Grouchy as always.
她醒了 依旧满腹怨气
Endlessly noisy.
无尽的嘈杂
Endlessly alive.
永远的活跃
She's all I really have.
她是真正属于我的
My only hope.
我唯一的希望
My only constant.
我唯一的永恒
The secrets of The Octopus died with him.
章鱼的秘密随着他的死一同消失
I don't know what I am or how long I got.
我不知道我是什么 还能活多久
Heck,  maybe I'll live forever.
嗯 也许我会永生
I hope not.
但我不想
That's nothing any man ought to have.
永生 不该发生在人的身上
ought to want.
人也不该去奢望永生
Denny Colt is dead. I'm something else now...
Denny Colt 死了 我不再是他
...and I can never give my heart to anyone but her.
而且除了她 我再无法付出真心
She will always be mine and I will always be hers.
她将永远属于我 我也会永远陪着她
She owns me,  body and soul.
她拥有我 拥有我的身心
She is the love of my life.
她是我的毕生挚爱
She is my city.
她是我的城市
And I...
而我...
...am her Spirit.
...是她的魂